WALKING ON THIN ICE
DRUG USE ISN’T JUST A MERE
DEVIATION BUT A SERIOUS CRIME
A SINGLE WRONG
CHOICE CAN DESTROY
AN INDIVIDUAL, A FAMILY,
AND SOCIETY AS A WHOLE
You nurse your husband and work at
the store every day. Aren't you tired?
Isn't it a hassle bringing Vaka
in small amounts every time?
You're doing the work twice.
Just put it at my place.
You live with Sua.
Do you really keep it at home?
Where?
You really want to know?
Sent it.
You could've just
said it out loud.
- What's this?
- A customer list.
It's divided into blacklisted,
new, and regular customers.
You should learn it.
We're a team now,
don't you trust me?
As if you do, huh?
I won't tell you until I earn
my 200 million, so forget it.
Whatever, showoff.
- The leaves are still falling.
- And?
I've worked as a server
in this neighborhood for three years.
It's gone now, but I worked at
Mijeong Restaurant across the street.
But I only just noticed
this big tree today.
You know, I really enjoy
waking up these days.
Caring for my husband and
working at the store isn't tiring.
I can't help but smile.
Watching the leaves sway
feels like the world has changed.
Maybe it's you who has changed.
PROTECTED TREE
ZELKOVA, 294 YEARS OLD
It has the same birthday as me.
How's that possible?
It's 300 years old.
I meant the day
this tree became protected.
In a way,
that's when it was reborn.
People recognize it
and call it by its name.
It went from just a tree
to a protected tree.
You asked me
what I wanted, right?
Let's just say
there's something I want to hear.
What's that?
Well done.
Even without parents, a college education,
and a permanent job...
Well done, Eunsoo.
You're good at everything you do.
Sitting under this protected tree,
I kind of feel like
I'm being protected, you know?
EPISODE 6
Who are you?
What do you want?
Tell me.
Where's our drug?
Let's wrap up and call it a day.
Hey, working overtime
won't make the bag appear.
Go home on time.
Husbands coming home late
and not helping with the kids
are all grounds for divorce.
I heard detectives
have a 40% divorce rate.
Exactly.
Even among us, there's you
and Detective Park.
At least I remarried, okay?
Keep me out of it.
- It's true, though.
- Have a good evening.
- I'll be on my way soon.
- Okay.
- Hurry up.
- Yes, sir.
Hey, come here.
You spoiled little brat.
- Didn't I tell you to educate her?
- But she's right.
You want a beating?
What drug?
You don't know?
Should I search the house?
Where could it be?
Where could you have hidden it?
Here? Huh?
Maybe in a place like this.
Bingo, found it.
Unbelievable.
How'd you even think of this?
You've been sleeping with it
all this time?
What about the money?
You sold some.
Give us the money.
That's all there is.
It was just... at the house.
I didn't know whose it was,
so I just kept it here.
You can take it all.
I'll never report on you.
I didn't report the drugs either, okay?
Then maybe we should
ask this one instead.
MOM
The number you have dialed
is not available...
Mom, I'm on my way.
I'll be there in thirty minutes.
How was Mr. Lee?
You're awake.
So, keep talking.
Put the knife down first,
then I'll talk.
- Talk first.
- Put the knife down.
- Who are you guys?
- Shut up before I stick you again.
Hey, that's enough.
Bro, what's wrong?
I'll kill you!
James?
Eunsoo! Get out of here!
Ah, you little thief.
You betrayed me first.
Donghyun?
Donghyun, why are you here?
Are you... Phantom?
Donghyun, please spare me.
I only used
a little bit of it.
Take it all, just take it.
I won't tell anyone.
Don't kill me, Donghyun.
Please...
Why did you bring that?
You never know.
Are you sure we shouldn't call?
If our boss gets involved,
it'll get messy.
We can handle it ourselves.
It'll be better.
MONEY-GRUBBER
DELETE
Let's finish this quickly.
Bro, what are you doing?
Please...
Please, Donghyun.
Take the money too.
Just spare me.
Donghyun, don't kill me.
Boss, what should I do with the thief?
- Kill 'em.
- Kill...?
They stole our stuff and sold it.
We can't leave them be.
We must set an example for the others.
Unless you and your brother
want to take the fall.
That's amazing!
Congratulations!
No, no!
Mom!
Mom, open the door!
Something must've stuck the door.
You're late.
Did you have a good time?
Yeah.
Why were you wearing that inside?
It's cold.
Is the heater turned off?
You should always have it on.
What happened?
Uh... I broke something.
- Mom.
- Yeah?
I'm sorry. I misunderstood.
I didn't know you did housekeeping.
I thought you were
earning money illegally.
I'm sorry.
I should've trusted you.
It's okay.
Sorry I didn't tell you earlier.
But I'm not ashamed of you.
You're my biggest pride, Mom.
You always were.
Expecting a call?
No, I was about to leave.
Why so scared?
Hey, come smoke with me.
I don't smoke.
Just do as I say.
What's this, boss?
The leftover after paying
my ex alimony.
I don't really need big money.
You were looking for a loan, right?
Buying the house
on a stretch was a mistake.
I have to pay millions in interest rates.
Forget about the principal.
That's life, man.
I can't take this money.
You gave me so much
at my child's first birthday.
Wanna know something?
I've seen a lot of people quit,
both voluntarily and not.
There are a lot of temptations.
You work your ass off
and get paid little.
The criminals you catch can make
your monthly salary in a day.
It drives you mad.
It's unfair.
They know this
and try to take advantage.
Remember Detective Park?
He was barely cleared two years ago.
They planted money in his trunk
and screwed him over.
They play games with our lives.
Why're you telling me this?
These days, it's hard to succeed
in the right way.
Hang in there.
There's still hope in this world
thanks to guys like you.
I'll definitely pay you back.
Just find the drug bag.
Our whole team
might get a promotion.
- Let's just finish this bag.
- What's in it?
Two soju and two snacks.
- No, we need more!
- What do you mean?
We need more alcohol!
Come here.
It's okay, it's broken.
Use this.
You killed him!
Mom, can I have ramen?
I'm going out to meet
Aunt Yeoju.
Hey, Sua.
I had to leave in a hurry.
Apparently, there's some urgent matter.
I'll be back soon.
Can you get me some spicy ramen?
Okay, got it.
See you later.
Tell me. How many are you,
and how much do you know?
You're so dead.
Get treatment first.
We're in a life-or-death situation.
Fuck the wound, okay?
Luckily, I don't think
their higher-ups know yet.
They were planning to report
after dealing with us.
I think this guy is the boss,
but he hasn't mentioned us yet.
Does that mean Donghyun
is part of Phantom?
We need a plan.
How should we deal with them?
Deal with them?
Yes, we can't leave them be.
They can't be locked up forever.
They'll kill us, okay?
Still...
We don't have time.
We need to decide.
The delivery truck
comes at seven, right?
This is difficult for me too.
If we don't kill them,
they'll kill us.
Do you want them
to get to your family?
SUA
It doesn't feel the same.
Everything feels weak
compared to Vaka.
Didn't he say he'd be here today?
You said he comes whenever you call.
Where is he?
Maybe I shouldn't have come.
I'm terrified right now.
I'll drop Sua off at her uncle's.
I'll be back.
Let's talk afterwards.
KANG HWIRIM
- Hey.
- Sup? Why're you ignoring me?
I'm dealing with some personal stuff.
You couldn't text me?
Everyone's here.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I wasn't thinking straight.
So when are you coming?
I can't make it today.
Bro. Bro!
Did you use it all up already?
It was quite a bit.
Are you fucking
calling me a junkie?
Hey! You think I'm like
those addicts?
Don't you dare get cocky on me!
Even last time, you didn't show up
and sent only a lawyer.
How dare you?
Keep your priorities straight!
Listen, I can't talk right now.
I'll call you later.
What did you say?
Say it again.
I dare you to say it!
Where...
To the hospital?
Boss...
Shit, the bag!
Huh?
Shut up and get your ass over here.
If you don't come today,
you're done. Got it?
Hello?
Ah, shit...
James. Hey, hey!
You bastard!
The number you have dialed
is not in service.
Boss, this is Junhyun!
Things got really messed up.
Can you come pick us up?
We need the doctor
who stitched my brother's finger.
What the hell happened?
Where are you?
This place is...
Junhyun.
Hello? Junhyun!
Hold on, a car's coming...
Fuck you, bastard...
Thank you.
Be a good girl.
- Bye.
- Okay.
I'm on my way now.
What?
The body came in early this morning.
Its clothes looked similar
to the ones on your wanted poster.
Similar, right? Lots of external injuries
and severe organ damage.
He died from bleeding
on the way to the hospital.
And the blood test
came back positive for drugs.
Sir, Major Crimes Unit 1
is transferring
the home invasion case to us.
Why?
They found drugs
in the dead suspect's system.
Phantom's new meth.
After their grandmother died,
they moved between relatives in Ansan.
When the older brother became of age,
they moved to Seoul.
To get a job.
Huh?
That's them.
They're the ones who fought
James at the station.
Wait, are these guys Phantom too?
- Which one died?
- I think the younger brother.
The other one is still unconscious.
They don't know
if he'll ever wake up.
Karma's a bitch.
Eunsoo, did you clean
the warehouse?
Nothing happened, okay?
It's all done.
Yeah, there was
a lot of dust piled up.
Make sure you act
like your usual self.
You sure are a diligent one.
I thought a cleaning company came by.
Good work.
By the way, any news of Donghyun?
He's not answering his phone.
Don't let the police or anyone else
connect you to that incident.
He hasn't shown up yet.
I didn't think he would
ditch us this fast.
Kids these days are unbelievable.
- Let me know if he calls.
- Sure.
Ah, hello.
Are you the owner?
I'm a police officer.
We're looking for Hwang Donghyun.
- When was the last time you saw him?
- About five days ago?
But he hasn't been answering
his phone since then.
So, you saw him when?
About five days ago.
He hasn't come to work since.
- And Kang Eunsoo?
- Eunsoo? There she is.
We meet again.
You know Hwang Donghyun too?
Wow, is there anyone
you don't know?
Then what about Phantom?
Eunsoo quit?
The cleaning job? Why?
I don't know.
She suddenly stopped coming.
The work was pretty nasty, I guess.
I'll wire you from now on.
Don't come here again.
Why? Do I embarrass you?
Not as much as someone who
begs his younger sister for money.
The number you dialed is not in service.
Please leave a message after the beep.
Eunsoo wouldn't quit just like that.
I keep getting impressed.
Chairman...
Please, I beg you.
Just this one time...
I'm begging you.
Please, Chairman...
Eunsoo works at Sua's art tutor?
Yeah, I was surprised
when I heard it from Sua.
She was better off cleaning
at the club.
But a housemaid for Sua's tutor?
It caused quite a bit
of a rumor at school.
Fake, of course.
Grapes are rich in antioxidants.
Try some.
Mr. Lee?
Mr. Lee!
Are you awake?
How did you get here?
Why didn't you
get your wound treated?
Because it's an obvious stab wound.
The hospital would've left a record.
So you went to school
in that condition?
You weren't answering my calls,
so I came by to find your front door open.
Why did you come?
We shouldn't be together right now.
The police came to the supermarket.
Okay, so what did you hear?
When they took him to the hospital,
it had already been too late.
That's actually good news for us.
Someone's dead.
Did you think we'd just earn
easy money and live happily ever after?
This isn't a simple hit-and-run.
The tint is too dark to see through.
No license plate either.
This was a planned crime.
If they're Phantoms disguised as robbers,
they're looking for their bag.
So, whoever they are after...
...must have the drug bag.
ACCOMPLICE?
MEDUSA CLEANER
KANG EUNSOO (42)
Hey, I have a question.
I saw my friend carrying pills inside
a highlighter. Where do they sell that?
If you tell me,
I'll send you my nudes.
Wow, nice!
How old?
Highlighter?
Do you mean Vaka?
- Vaka?
- That's how they call Phantom's meth.
MINTCANDY22...
That's the seller's ID.
HASN'T BEEN ACTIVE THOUGH
Shit, the seller's inactive.
They've gone off the grid.
- I'll ask the Cybercrime Unit for help.
- Okay.
Isn't this an opportunity for us?
We can pin this on Phantom more easily.
Just like you said.
Pick.
Is it them or your family?
- Both.
- What?
I can save both.
I just need to persuade Donghyun.
Do you really think that's possible?
Donghyun worked with me
for over half a year.
He's not the type to work
for some gang.
Maybe he was trying
to get out of Phantom.
It doesn't make sense for him
to work so hard to get that big job!
Then what about Phantom?
Say you convince them.
What about Phantom?
You saw the texts.
They have a boss.
They'll keep sending people.
The police...
What if we use the police?
If Donghyun tells the police
about the Phantom,
and make them get arrested,
we won't have anyone chasing us!
A man was killed.
But that changes nothing.
We stick to our plan.
Besides, you didn't kill him.
And neither did I.
We've done nothing wrong.
Sir, could this be an internal conflict?
When I first arrested
Phantom's foot soldiers three years ago,
they didn't know each other
nor shared information.
We still don't know
who their boss is.
That's why they're called Phantom.
Keep going.
It's the same
as with Kim Bongnam.
What if James,
the bucket hat woman,
and the hit-and-run driver
are all Phantoms?
What if they're just fighting
to get the drug bag?
HWANG JUNHYUN
The number you have
dialed cannot be reached.
Please leave a message
after the beep.
HWANG DONGHYUN
Chief!
We've located
Hwang Donghyun's phone!
Really?
Let's go!
BOSS
HWANG DONGHYUN
He's half Vietnamese
and has been quiet for a few years.
He's got three prior convictions
for drug trafficking.
And now he's running
a noodle shop.
- Is this Hwang's phone location?
- Yes.
Then this bastard has to be
the hit-and-run driver!
DO GYUMAN
Let's ask him in person.
Eunsoo?
Yeoju...
Why the shoehorn?
Sua said she went to her uncle's,
and was worried about you.
Why haven't you been
answering my calls?
Wow, samgyetang!
- Did that lady give us this too?
- Yeah.
I just wanted... to live, you know?
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
AUTOPSY REPORT
1. DEATH BY MULTIPLE EXTERNAL INJURIES
2. DEATH BY MULTIPLE ORGAN DAMAGE
3. SHOCK AND BLOOD LOSS
4. BLOOD TEST RESULTS...
HWANG DONGHYUN
I made this using
Korean native chicken.
So plump, right?
Try it.
Eunsoo, are you crying?
What's wrong?
Eunsoo.
- If anything happens, call me.
- Okay, thanks.
My father always told me.
If you steal from others,
you'll always pay the price.
But for some people,
despite knowing the price,
there's a reason they can't stop.
Who is it?
Don't worry about it.
Didn't I tell you that we're done?
Fuck off, bastard.
The high doesn't hit the same, right?
Not like how it was?
You'll be needing me again.
CALLER ID BLOCKED
Whatever it is,
the joy of gaining something...
...is always less
than the pain of losing it.
WALKING ON THIN ICE
100 mil every week?
I have to keep doing this?
What was that you delivered?
I'll find the culprit.
We haven't figured out
how the Phantom has our intel, right?
This is the blackmailer's photo,
and this is the one I just took.
What if it's someone around us?
What's with your face?
What did you do last night?
If they have both motive and reason...
Was it really you?
You're the money-grubber,
aren't you?